NYSUT Legislative Department Files. 6174/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Costello, John, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Memo from Costello to legislative director Ray Skuse reporting on strategy session at UFT re governance, capital improvements, school aid, violence, and pension issues, December 16, 1993; memo from Costello to Skuse discussing state aid to NYC schools, December 13, 1993; notes from meeting of Special Act school local presidents, November 30, 1993; memo re school-related personnel issues, November 12, 1993; letter to members from NYSUT president and executive vice president, opposing secession of Staten Island from NYC, October 25, 1993; letter to members urging vote for Jim Florio in New Jersey gubernatorial election, October 25; information re retirement issues; other chronological correspondence
- Costello, John, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Chronological correspondence re phone banks (rental) from Democratic State Committee, endorsement procedures, meeting of Special Act local presidents, salary issues for 4201 schools; policy papers re tax reform, teacher centers
- Bozzella, John, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Memo to UFT president Sandy Feldman from assistant director for NYC John Bozzella re talking points for legislative breakfast, February 1, 1988; text of proposed legislation; memorandum of support re proposed legislation to allow retired NYC police and firefighters who become teachers to opt for NYC Teachers Retirement System
- Costello, John, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Chronological correspondence re Assembly hearing on small (Hurd) cities and budget vote, October 16, retiree health insurance, resolutions for NYSUT Representative Assembly
- Costello, John, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  List of key NYSUT program and support bills approved since August 29, 1988; memo from Costello to legislative director Ray Skuse re Hurd (small city) school aid formula and budget vote question, March 3, 1989; outline for remarks at health insurance hearing; summary of Coalition Finance Committee meeting, January 9, 1989; discussion of Yonkers Emergency Financial Control Board impact on collective bargaining, April 12, 1989; memo re 1989 Representative Assembly resolutions; draft text for VOTE/COPE brochures
- Costello, John, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Memo to Ray Skuse re conversations with Senate and Assembly Education Committee staff, April 6; letter to Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan, indicating NYSUT endorsement of candidacy, August 15; letters to member re endorsements by NYSUT Board of Directors; legislative updates, including summary of meeting re NYC legislative concerns, November 7; letter to legislators, urging substantial increase in state aid to education
- Costello, John, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Background information re Hurd (small city schools) bills of interest; memo re NYSUT's legislative goals for 1987; memos to Retirees' Organizing Committee (ROC) re Supplemental Pension Bill, health insurance, and related legislation; memo to Ray Skuse re support activities for Committee of 100 lobbying, February 26; invoices to treasurers of various candidate election committees for phone bank use; memos re Public Employee Conference legislative breakfast
- Costello, John, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Materials re Hurd (small city) school aid; correspondence with Retirees' Organizing Committee (ROC) re pharmaceutical assistance program; other monthly legislative updates to ROC; agreement on the use of telephone bank for political calls; phone bank script; letter to members urging vote to re-elect Assembly member Nick Spano; list of names and addresses of Board of Regents; outline of legislative program for 1986; memos to NYSUT Executive Committee re 1986-87 Executive Budget, state aid proposal; UFT requests re state aid 1985-86; list of status of bills (passed Assembly only, passed Senate only, passed both), December 11, 1985; suggestions by Costello to legislative staff for amendment language to legislation re students with handicapping conditions, December 6, 1985; memos by Costello re school bus safety legislation, special education reform, revenue sharing, teacher salaries; flyers re Democratic presidential primary candidates, "Walter Mondale on the Issues," "A Closer Look at Hart's Record"; Assembly Republican White Paper Summary
- Frantz, Ronald, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Updates on Congressional District liaison activities; evaluation of Wharton School management training program; memos re salary legislation for 4201 schools; description of VOTE/COPE award criteria; list of VOTE/COPE contributions by service center 1980-86; memo re VOTE/COPE retiree project; agenda for VOTE/COPE coordinators meeting, November 6; draft letter to local presidents urging support for VOTE/COPE; memo and information re NYS presidential primary; memo re legislation affecting Special Act schools; list of NY members of Congress, noting party affiliation and whether endorsed by NYSUT, with major locals, ED directors, and VOTE/COPE members in district; list of names and addresses of members of Political Action Committee; list of pending bills in Senate and Assembly, status, and NYSUT position; memo to Sen. Tarky Lombardi with attached language of bill re provision of psychological services in schools, urging that he reintroduce it, March 12
- Frantz, Ronald, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Lists of VOTE/COPE contributions by service center; related correspondence with locals and individuals; document, "Conducting a Successful VOTE/COPE Campaign"; description of Legislative Department; memo to NYSUT legal counsel expressing concern over liability for bus drivers in proposed legislation requiring use of seat belts by students in school buses, May 21, 1986; related correspondence, December 18, 1984; list of VOTE/COPE regional coordinators, with recommendations for reappointment or replacement, January 27, 1986; background information for Special Act (institutional) schools meeting, December 4, 1984; related correspondence; list of NYSUT top priority items for 1985 legislative session, October 2, 1984; 1984 Legislative Agenda for NYSUT's SRP [school-related personnel] Members; correspondence re voter registration drive
- Lewis, Alan, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Final document for legislators, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity"; NYSUT proposed legislation for supplemental retirement allowance, April 18; update on supplemental pension bills, August 18; list of bills of interest that passed both houses, August; memos re Employees' Retirement System consultant training
- Lewis, Alan, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  1995 Bills of Interest Passed Both Houses as of July 6; memo re implementation of resolutions passed at 1995 Representative Assembly and referred to Legislative Department, August 17; materials re early retirement incentive, supplemental pensions
- Kafka, Emanuel, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Federal Legislative Highlights, first session, 101st Congress, 1989; legislative priorities of NYSUT and AFT in the 101st Congress; Federal Legislative Report; memo from Kafka to legislative director Ray Skuse re new state legislative program items, January 18, 1989; memo re lobbying results against the comprehensive child care bill, October 11, 1989; report on congressional legislative reception, March 22, 1989
- Kafka, Emanuel, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  List of votes by individual members of Congress on key issues; resolutions by 1988 NYSUT Representative Assembly, with draft cover letter to AFT director of legislation, urging support; memo re key AFL-CIO legislative issues in 1988, with attached voting record of NY congressional delegation; results of phone bank in Nassau and Suffolk counties re Dukakis/Bush presidential race, November 2, 1988; items included in U.S. Senate 1987-88 voting record; list of NY congressional candidates, indicating NYSUT endorsement status, November 1, 1988; list, "Items from the Republican Platform that May be Unjurious to Our Members"; memo from Kafka to Skuse, "Bills I Recommend That We Try to Achieve This Year," May 1, 1988
- Kafka, Emanuel, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Memo re AFL-CIO meeting with representatives of candidates for Democratic nomination for president, December 7, 1987; instructions for obtaining signatures for candidate designating petitions; NYSUT resolutions re federal legislation, with cover letter to AFT Director of Legislation, November 3, 1987; summary of delegate selection process for Democratic nomination; memo detailing proposed expansion of catastrophic coverage by Medicare by House Ways and Means Committee, April 23, 1987
- Kafka, Emanuel, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  List of 1986 "Invisible Victories," harmful state legislation successfully blocked by NYSUT; Selected Items from the 1986 Tax Reform Act re Teacher Pensions; 1986 Tax Reform Act and How It Affects Teachers; voting record of Senate and House members for 1985, as reported by AFL-CIO; memo from Kafka reporting lack of cooperation by some members in response to request to make phone calls for Guy Velella special election, April 30, 1986; letters from Kafka to individual members of Congress re tax-deferred annuity retirement plans, November 6, 1985; memo from Kafka to NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese summarizing legislative accomplishments affecting BOCES, October 17, 1985; memo from Kafka re Special Education Reform Act of 1985; other memos evaluating aspects of wide range of issues
- Hartnell, Jeff, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  Lists of towns by NYS congressional, Senate, and Assembly district
- Kafka, Emanuel-Clinton Health Care, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  Materials re Clinton health care plan; list of members of NY congressional delegation, with contact information; Federal Legislative Highlights, second session, 101st Congress, 1990
- Gigi Georges, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  Memo to Ray Skuse re priority pension items for 1992 session; statement of opposition to proposed grant program that would redirect funds from public to private schools; faxed document to Skuse, UFT legislative program and support bills that have been signed into law
- Ron Frantz, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Chronological correspondence file of assistant to executive vice president re phone bank operation, pre-RA planning, VOTE/COPE material preparation, status of voter registration project; notes from board/manager retreat of September 19, 1988; report of VOTE/COPE activities at 1988 Representative Assembly; RA resolutions; report on Coalition for Economic Priorities Steering Committee meeting, March 8, 1989; letter of resignation, June 6, 1989
- Read File A-L, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient
- Read File M-Z, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Read File A-I, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Read File J-M, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Read File Mc-R, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Read File S-W, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Read File XYZ, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Read File A-E, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Read File F-K, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Read File L-Q, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Read File R-Z, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Read File A-F, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Read File G-K, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Read File L-N, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Read File O-S, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Read File T-Z, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Read File A-L, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Read File M-Z, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Read File A-E, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Read File F-L, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Read File M, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Read File N-Z, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Read File A-L, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Read File M-Z, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- John Costello Chronological Files, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Outgoing correspondence
- Representative Assembly Box Labels, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  RA inventory sheet; instructions; labels
- RA Agenda, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  To-do list; agenda; Local Presidents' Conference agenda; memos re reception for NYS congressional delegation, Executive Committee meeting
- RA Travel Assignments, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Correspondence re housing and travel accommodations
- RA Floor Plan, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Convention hall floor plan; list of key staff telephone numbers
- RA Invites, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Letters to NYS elected officials, inviting them to speak
- RA Print Orders, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Print orders for postcards to elected representatives, and other materials
- RA Proposed Constitution Amendments and Resolutions (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  List of resolutions and assigned departments for implementation; booklet, Implementation of Actions by the 2003 Representative Assembly
- RA Proposed Constitution Amendments and Resolutions (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Text of resolutions
- RA PAC Center, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Application for display space for Political Action Center at 2003 Representative Assembly; related memo
- RA VOTE/COPE, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  List of locals qualifying for awards based on levels of contribution per member; letters from NYSUT secretary-treasurer Alan Lubin to VOTE/COPE members re Representative Assembly
- RA Intros and Speeches, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Text of speech (unattributed), "March on Albany: Find a Way"; text of introductions of speakers (Sen. Charles Schumer, Gov. Howard Dean, Sen. John Edwards, Sen. John Kerry, Sen. Hillary Rodham Clinton, Rep. Richard Gephart); draft of speech by NYSUT president Tom Hobart; video production directions; Power Point presentation printouts; CD-ROMS and diskette
- RA Other, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Invoice for computer giveaway; Preview newsletter for Representative Assembly; web pages announcing convention and agenda; e-mail memos
- RA Convention Materials Mailed, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  Booklets, RA Resolutions Due to Expire in 2003; Convention Call; Local Presidents' Conference; Constitution and Bylaws effective April 2002; Delegate and Alternate Bulletin, February 19, 2003, and March 12, 2002; program; memo re delegate mailings
- RA Invites, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  Letters of invitation to elected officials to speak at convention; tentative program
- RA Letters, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Tentative program; proposed deadlines and policies; letter from president Hobart to Election District directors requesting credentials committee nominations, September 5, 2003
- RA Print Orders (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Print orders for Kerry flyers and other materials
- RA Print Orders (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  Text of resolutions by various committees
- RA Solidarity Event (Rally), 2004 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- RA VOTE/COPE, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  List of VOTE/COPE coordinators attending Representative Assembly; facilitative correspondence
- RA PAC Center, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  Letters from executive vice president Alan Lubin, thanking members for staffing Political Action Center; form letters for faxing to federal and state elected officials on a wide range of issues
- RA Intros and Speeches, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  Text of speech by Alan Lubin, "Together We Can Do Anything"; bullet points for retiree luncheon, re Medicare; Power Point presentation printouts; diskette
- RA Local Presidents' Conference, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  Facilitator's questions for workshop, Political Mobilization for 2004 Elections; text of speech by John Costello; list of staff attending workshops; materials for Local Presidents' Conference binders, re Kerry and Bush, including questions and answers re AFT endorsement of Kerry; print request orders
- RA Other, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  Newsletter, RA Reporter; revised RA Team meeting agenda, January 4; related correspondence
- RA Convention Materials Mailed, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  Booklets, Convention Call, Local Presidents' Conference, Constituency Awards: Call for Nominations, 2004 Community Service Awards, Resolutions Due to Expire in 2004; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws effective April 2003, Retiree Council Presidents' Conference; camera-ready mockup of conference logo
- RA Agenda Information, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  Representative Assembly program; Convention Call; program for Pre-Representative Assembly Local Presidents' Conference; action items
- RA Correspondence, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  Letters of invitation to elected officials
- RA Give-Aways, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  Letter to director of state affairs for Sen. Chuck Schumer, asking permission to use Schumer's likeness on a coin for distribution at reception at Representative Assembly, February 25; memo indicating that a fundraising raffle was illegal in NYS
- RA Memos, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  List of Democratic officials invited to presentation of Distinguished Service Award to Hillary Clinton; recap of discussion at video planning meeting, December 10, 1998; list of responses by political leaders invited to attend Representative Assembly; memo from NYSUT Office of General Counsel re legality of raffles, February 19, 1999; memo from counsel re use of public officials' image on coins, February 19, 1999; facultative correspondence
- RA Floor Plan, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Layout of Niagara Falls Convention Center main floor and foyer
- RA-Other, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Notes for speech by Alan Lubin; checklists; newspaper clipping re First Lady Hillary Clinton and Rep. Nita Lowy, speculation on Senate run; Thursday proceedings newsletter, featuring Hillary Clinton; NYSUT Constitution, effective May 1998
- RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Text of proposed NYSUT constitutional amendments and resolutions arranged by committee
- RA Agenda Information, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Tentative program for Representative Assembly
- RA Correspondence, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart, thanking VOTE/COPE and Political Action Committee coordinators, noting gift of jacket
- RA Floor Plan, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Floor plan for NY Hilton convention area
- RA Give-Aways, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- RA Invites, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  Letters of invitation from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to elected officials to attend or speak at Representative Assembly; thank-you letters from Lubin to staff who operated Political Action Center
- RA Memos, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Memos re assignments and daily staff functions, last-minute details; daily convention summaries; delegate survey; agendas; housing information
- RA Other, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Tentative staff list; invitation list of elected officials
- RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  Working draft, Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions; blank forms for proposed resolutions and constitutional amendments; NYSUT Constitution, effective April 1999
- RA Agenda, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Agendas and staff assignments
- RA Delegate Bulletins, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  Memo
- RA Emails, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Staff list; correspondence re housing and transportation logistics, memorabilia, signage, and decorations, CWA staff overtime
- RA Invites, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  Lists of invited guests (confirmed, declined, no reply); letters of invitation to elected officials
- RA Letters, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  Form letter soliciting volunteers for Political Action Center, with attached list; letter to Office of the State Comptroller re anticipated remarks to RA, giving background on NYSUT and current issues of concern
- RA Memos, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  Memo re display space, with attached application form; memo re political action video
- RA Print Orders, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  Print order requests for letters and postcards to elected representatives
- RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  Working draft, Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions
- RA VOTE/COPE Shirts, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  Letters informing locals that they qualified for shirts, based on contributions; invoice
- RA Other, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  NYSUT 2001 Representative Assembly Follow-Up Survey Report; tentative program; convention floor plan
- RA Agenda, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  Agenda; pocket program; flyer invitation to Legislative Department staff reception; staff assignments
- RA Delegate Bulletins, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  Saturday summary of proceedings
- RA Emails, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- RA Floor Plan, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  New York Hilton convention floor plans
- RA Invites, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  Text of introductions for political officials, noting contributions to education; staff writing assignments; letters of invitation to elected officials
- RA Letters, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  Form letter soliciting volunteers for Political Action Center, with attached list
- RA Print Orders, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  Print order requests for postcards to elected representatives re Medicare
- RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  Revised constitution, with cover letter to NYSUT Board of Directors from president Tom Hobart; text of adopted and referred resolutions, organized by assigned committees for implementation; NYSUT Constitution, effective May 2001; RA Resolutions due to expire in 2002; convention call; program for Pre-RA Local Presidents' Conference; Delegate and Alternate Bulletin
- RA Other, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  Text of convention speech by Alan Lubin; text of speech for retiree luncheon; list of VOTE/COPE regional campaign coordinators; list of locals qualifying for awards based on contributions; text of introductions for political officials; memos re special event featuring entertainment by comedy troupe Capitol Steps; facilitative correspondence, noting heightened security at Hilton
- 15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook- Monday, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  Research and Educational Services Resource Guide on CD; Local Leaders' Guide 2005-2006; Participants' Handbook for 15th New Local Presidents' Conference; A Guide to Field and Legal Services; Guide to Program Services; materials for general sessions; NYSUT Mission Statement
- 15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook-Tuesday, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective April 2005; AFT 2004 Constitution and Bylaws; description of NYSUT Benefit Trust; materials for general sessions
- 15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook-Wednesday, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  Making the News, Framing the Message: A NYSUT Local Leaders Guide to Handling the News Media; 2005 Legislative Program; list of members of Political Action Committee; brochure, When Everything Seems Stacked Against Us, VOTE-COPE Tips the Scales; VOTE-COPE Instruction Manual
- Lubin Calendar, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  January 2001-November 2001
- Lubin Calendar, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  December 2001-December 2002
- Lubin Calendar, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  January 2003-December 2003
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Vote/Cope, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms; bullet points for Board Report 3/12/99 re Report of Task Force on Minority Involvement in NYSUT and Affiliated Locals and other items
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE
- Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)